Ian Price

SEATTLE, WA 98118 (928) 600-0358 IAN@REDMOUNTAINSOFTWARE.COM Personal site

About

Full-stack software engineer, population geographer, product designer, and data necromancer finding joy in making the complexities of the world accessible to all. Deep technical expertise in PostgreSQL, Typescript/Vue, Python/Django, data visualization, and responsive user interfaces.

Specialist in taking products from zero to one and transforming companies through software.

Experience

DECEMBER 2023 - PRESENT (Full-time)

Galvanick, Seattle, WA - Senior Software Engineer

AWS, Typescript, Vue, Vite, Vitest, Go, OpenAPI, PostgreSQL, Docker

- Designed and created all customer applications, powering demos and finalizing POC (and securing POV) with a Fortune 100 company within 8 months of hire.
- Technical lead in database development, re-designing PostgreSQL schemas and integrating migration system for optimization and increased development velocity.
- Mentored engineers in full-stack development while advising founders on product design, architectural decisions, and best practices.

AUGUST 2020 - SEPTEMBER 2023 (Full-time)

AquaSeca, San Jose, CA (remote) – *Staff Software Engineer (Founding team)*GCP, Typescript, Vue, Webpack, Jest, Python, Pytest, Flask, PostgreSQL, Firebase, Docker, Kubernetes

- Devised foundational libraries, internal practices, product design, and conventions for the technical team, turning a lab idea into a fully-fledged product and company.
- Using Python, Vue, and PostgreSQL (in addition to GCP services), created platforms for consumer management of complex AI-driven IoT devices, tackling extensive UX challenges and enabling the development of our most complex feature sets.
- Architected and optimized databases through optimization, partitioning, and sharding, increasing performance four-fold and supporting years of future growth.
- Acted as technical chief-of-staff, performed training and user experience research for critical clients (both prior to and after product-to-market), evangelized product strengths and company image, and performed on-site installations.
- Designed and implemented auto-documenting APIs for external ease of use, leading to a dozen integrations of the AquaSeca product into external platforms.

AquaSeca was acquired by Alert Labs in 2024.

AUGUST 2012 - AUGUST 2020 (Full-time)

Thermaline, Seattle, WA - Head of Software and I.T.

AWS, Javascript, Python, Django, Vue, PyQT, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Bash

- As the first and sole technical staff member, designed and built Bigfoot, an internal MRP,
 CRM, and sales platform still in use today, fundamentally changing a decades-old business while multiplying profitability and lowering order-to-ship time by 80%.
- Designed and built first-in-industry engineer-to-order e-commerce systems, directly responsible for millions of dollars of sales per year since 2015.
- Created a series of engineering and quoting tools, including technical drawing generators and fluid dynamics engines, enabling R&D and new product creation.

JULY 2015 - AUGUST 2020 (Part-time)

Red Mountain Software, Seattle, WA – *Owner and Software Engineer* AWS, Heroku, Javascript, React, Python, Django, PostgreSQL, Bash

Red Mountain Software operated as a part-time endeavor while maintaining a full-time workload elsewhere. Red Mountain Software served over a dozen clients.

- Performed prototype builds for early startups, leading to multiple rounds of funding.
- Built one-off web applications for multiple engineering firms, an IT hardware company, a subscription box service, and a food manufacturer.
- Created specs and design documents to ensure delivery of final products while managing client expectations, contractor resources, and release schedules.

JULY 2007 - AUGUST 2010 (Full-time)

United States Census Bureau, Seattle, WA – *Geographer* ArcGIS, Python, Customized tooling

- As 5-state regional lead of legally contentious programs (PSAP, LUCA), completed program work for the decennial census 5 months ahead of schedule.
- Managed map printing operations for regional field offices, coordinating complex and deadline-oriented timelines while building automation scripts.
- Built tooling, using Python, to evaluate technical and procedural issues with government-submitted proposals, adopted nationally across all regional offices.

Education

University of Washington, Seattle, WA – *Master's in Geographic Information Systems*Specialized in geospatial analysis and interactive data product design, graduating with a 4.0 GPA.

Western Washington University, Bellingham, WA – *B.A. in Geography*

Member of Gamma Rho, an international honors society for geographers. Graduated with a 3.9 GPA.